Last week I came across this website and
there are two types of people in the
world. The first who would just look at
this website and be like okay that's a
cool site and move on with their life
and the second kind which is like me who
look at this website and the first
thought I had was how hard could it be
to recreate it and that's exactly the
question I'm going to try and answer
today. From my experience coding for a
lot of years, I'm pretty sure it's not
going to be as simple as you think it
is. So, let's find out.
This website looks absolutely insane and
there's so much we could do. So, I
really need to narrow down my focus for
the sake of this video. And I'm going to
try and recreate this homepage element.
So this section which is basically his
face moving up and down as you move the
mouse and also as I move the mouse the
helmet patterns change and it moves
according to my cursor and also the
background is moving as you can see and
I'm going to need all the help possible.
So I'm going to open up Chat LM who also
the sponsors of this video. Out of all
of the models that they offer I think
for this case I'm going to use their
clots on 4.5. The first step is going to
be to plan. So, I'm going to first
figure out what is the laziest way that
I can recreate his website. I'm hoping
to be able to copy out all of the HTML
CSS. I'm going to use the microphone
mode instead of typing it out cuz I just
find it so much easier.
Okay, the first option is browser dev
tools, which is the laziest mode where I
just copy paste all of the HTML and the
index files as well. So, this is what I
was thinking of, but maybe there's a
faster way for me to do that. We know
where to start. I'm going to use this
command, run it on my terminal, and try
to copy paste his exact website, try to
run it locally.
Yeah, I remember when I was an idiot and
I said that we could probably just copy
the files. That's clearly not what we
can do. So, I did try to clone
everything and of course, as expected, I
tried to run the index file on the
browser directly, the easiest way. It
was obviously not going to work the
first time around because the first
error we got was 43 from the server. So
that's essentially they're giving us a
forbidden error for the external
JavaScript which makes total sense why
they would want to protect that and it
probably just allows requests that come
only from landonor.com server and they
block requests that come from any other
server. Another problem that I was
getting was that these RI files were not
being loaded properly. And even though I
copied them over manually, it's still
not working because this is supposed to
load the animations, but somehow not
still loading. I'm going to go back to
Claude and try to brainstorm other ways
for me to do this in a lazy way. Yes, we
hit a blocker, but I feel like this will
go somewhere.
>> A few moments later.
>> Oh my god, it actually works. Let me
explain to you guys how I fixed it. I
did start off by mirroring the site with
wget, but this only ended up getting the
HTML and the CSS. While it was good
enough, this particular site actually
has a lot of heavy reliance on
JavaScript and 3D web. So, these were
kind of two separate problems. I
realized to get all of the JavaScript, I
actually had to manually download all of
the files. And then when it came to the
3D WebGL, this turned out to be quite a
heavy part. There were a bunch of things
used. So they basically had decoders,
they had 3D models, they had textures,
lighting, all of these. And I had to
manually fetch them and store them
locally for this whole thing to work.
But it wasn't too much effort. It was
mostly just a lot of looking where's the
error, downloading the file, the errors,
looking again, what file is erroring,
and that whole loop again and again. But
now we're at the stage where I actually
have the entire website running locally.
Huh? It was working. What changed?
I really should go sleep. But I'm facing
this really weird issue. Let me try to
explain to you what's happening. So I'm
going to refresh my page with the
inspect tab open. And everything works
fine. Right. I close it. I refresh
again. And it seems to work. But once I
close the inspect, it stops loading. And
then I go back to the console logs and
there's errors about failing to load the
resources.
Super weird. Never experienced something
like this. I have a feeling this has to
do with loading issues. I decided to
explain it to the LLM and it actually
suggests that it's a caching a timing
issue. I do have a a ton of assets in
the code like not even just images so
many different JS files that I have
downloaded. So all that could be causing
my Chrome to behave really slowly.
[Music]
It's happening in Safari as well. Like
the moment I close the inspect tab, it
stops loading.
Okay, I really need to go to sleep. I'm
going to come back to this tomorrow
morning and then we're going to try and
fix this and figure out what's going on.
It's a new day, but the same problem.
I'm going to give myself half an hour
this morning, try and fix this stupid
issue where it only works in the inspect
mode, and hopefully we find a solution.
If we don't, then I'm going to have to
regroup
and think of how we proceed next.
I fixed it. It works. So the issue was
that the moment the screen got wider, it
actually needed to load more textures
because the animation changes depending
on the responsiveness of the website and
there was one package that I was missing
and it wasn't loading correctly when the
size was a bit larger. So had to do
quite a bit of debugging with that. But
eventually we reached a stage where I'm
able to load the site locally. And I
also tried to remove all of the assets
that I don't need from this hero
section. So if I try to scroll like I'm
trying right now, there's nothing that I
see in the rest of the website.
Everything is kind of empty. Okay. Other
than this part, I didn't remove it. So
now I can tweak what we have now to make
it look like something that would fit in
my portfolio website. The first thing I
need is an image. I'm going to use AI to
help me generate that. and Bucky Chat LM
also allows me to create images. So, I'm
going to use out of all of the different
models that they have. Probably going to
use N Banana actually. So, I'm going to
take a photo of myself first. I took a
photo with three different angles and
I'm going to give it to Nano Banana
along with Lando Norris's image so that
it can potentially create an image that
looks sort of like his but it's my face
on it.
Now, before using Nano Banana to
generate the AI image of myself, I need
to create a prompt that I can send to
Nan Banana. I'm going to use GPT5 to
help me create it because I think it's
pretty good in creating prompts that you
can send to other LLMs or other models.
It has the finalized prompt. I'm going
to copy paste it here. In the meanwhile,
I'm going to try and modify all of the
text of this, like remove things like
his name, these side elements, the
McLaren logo and stuff, cuz I want this
to be more like my site, so I don't
really need all this. These are the
images generated. They look pretty
blurry, so I've asked it to come up with
more ones that are higher resolution.
Technically, it did do what we asked it
to do. It did combine the Landon Norris
image with my images, but I want it to
look a bit more professional. Okay, now
it just gave me something that looks
nothing like me. I'm going to try and
come up with a different prompt to fix
this. So far, I've removed all of the
random buttons here. Removed it. Okay,
perfect. Now, I want to try and replace
his face with mine. Hopefully, it's just
an image change, but maybe it's
something more than that. I asked you to
come up with a funky sweater and it came
up with this. I think it looks cool. I'm
going to go ahead with this image, but
we need to convert it to webp style. So,
let's open another tab of chat lm. Now,
going back to what's the fastest way to
convert a PNG or JPEG into WEBP format.
[Music]
Great. I have it in WEBP format now. So,
I'm going to push this over in my code.
Is the moment of truth. I'm going to
open it incognito tab.
go to my local host.
[Music]
Oh, my image appears. Okay, clearly it's
not the right fit, but the gist is
there, but there's like this weird
overlay on top of my face, like some
kind of weird dirt effect, so the skin
looks really dirty. It wasn't as simple
as just changing the image. I also had
to modify some of these KTX2
files as well. Okay, let me try to show
you what I'm trying to fix here. So,
this is what Lando's website looks like
where his face is pretty perfect fit to
the center of the screen. And currently,
this is what mine looks like. So,
clearly the rest of my face here is not
visible. And after looking at the code,
I realized that this is probably because
in the webp file, the way that a lot of
these assets are loaded, they tend to
have this alpha
uh base layer followed by a depth, which
gives you that 3D effect. But I do need
to modify all of these other things as
well, like this roughness. a few moments
later.
>> So, I tried a bunch of different things
in these next few hours, like trying to
fix the texture, but I ended up breaking
it a couple of times. Like, this looks
horrible. And then finally, what worked
was going on Canva and creating a custom
shadow, which now looks so much better
than what we had before. Like, my face
is not blocked anymore. Then, I wanted
to fix the helmet colors to match my
style. So, I used AI to create that for
me. But, I wasn't entirely happy with
how it looked because there were so many
McLaren logos. So then I went on Canva,
manually went to edit things out that I
didn't like, modified all of these
different things, and then we ended up
with ta. I think it looks really not
bad. Like there's quite a few things to
fix, but let's talk about the positives
first. Like when I hover over the
helmet, I'm really happy with the design
of the helmet. You see Life of Gors
there. I love the color. I love the
design that we've come up with and also
removing all of the logos. So really
happy with that. And as I move my face
up and down, the transition's really
smooth. And I'm quite proud of that. And
also able to view all of my different
hair strands, everything. And the
background also looks really good. We
didn't manage to break the animations in
the background. So that's a success in
my books. Now, what can be fixed?
There's definitely a weird texture on
top of my face that you can see as well,
both on my nose, the top part of my
forehead, and also the neck. I presume
this comes from the shadow effect from
Lando's beard. And since I don't have a
beard, I do need to remove this whole
shadow effect. And that's the downside
when you copy someone's code instead of
building something yourself. As I scroll
down, there is another thing that I'm
quite proud of, which is this whole
effect. And this would fit so well in a
portfolio website. And I know the image
itself looks dirty. Again, we need to
fix that. But if you just think of it
conceptually, this was really amazing.
So I'm really proud of what we have come
up with and I feel a lot more confident
to work on top of this project and
modify it to add new things. It's like
dark outside already. I don't know if
you can tell how exhausted I am. This is
another silly project, but I don't think
it was that silly after all because I do
feel like I learned new stuff. I learned
about new libraries that are used in
motion animations as well as 3D effects.
And most importantly, thank you so much
Chat LM for sponsoring this video. They
have a bunch of models, whether it's
textbased models or image models. And
they also have their own deep agent. And
you get access to all of these models at
a very, very low cost price. So
definitely check them out in the link in
the description box below. And with that
being said, thank you so much for
watching. I will see you in the next
one.